dotrising.com 2015-06-10

# Cookie & Privacy Policy | .rising

**.rising is committed to protecting your privacy and we therefore take care over any information gathered through our website (www.dotrising.com). We do, like many other sites, use ‘cookies’ to help us gather data; this page provides more information on the type of information we collect, what it is used for, and how you can make any changes.**

**What information do we gather?**  
Other than the Subscription Sign Up box section of our site, dotrising.com is an informational (non-transactional) website and we do not actively collect information of a personal nature from our visitors. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the EU Privacy and Communications Directive). This includes information submitted voluntarily by you through a form or gathered automatically as you visit this website.

We do, however, gather some information through the use of ‘cookies’ and this is detailed below. Gathered information may be kept indefinitely as administrative and research material but we do not make any efforts to extrapolate personal or individual data from this.

**What is a ‘cookie’?**  
Cookies are small text files a website places on your computer when you first visit. There are several types of cookies that help websites improve your customer experience by remembering relevant information — for example, a shopping site will use cookies to ensure your shopping basket ‘remembers’ the items you have added.

.rising uses cookies on its website to collect information about how visitors use the website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages.

These are placed by Google Analytics and are completely safe and secure and will never contain any sensitive or personal information.

Google Analytics is the software package we use to track visitor usage of our site, including overall numbers and user journeys. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. This information allows us to understand the composite interests of our users and regularly adapt and improve our site to meet their needs.

If you would like to disable Google Analytics from placing a cookie file on your computer, you can follow the instructions [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout), on Google’s site. www.dotrising.com will still work and you will be able to access all of the information within the site. However, by disabling cookies, or certain types of cookie, you may hinder your user experience on this and other websites, or prevent them from working entirely. This will have an impact on our ability to understand how our site is accessed by our visitors, and therefore impact our ability to improve how we develop what we offer our visitors to the site.

Cookies may also be used to improve the user experience and to enable some of the functionality provided by this website.

Please note that some cookies may be placed by third party service providers who perform some of these functions (or other services) for us. Cookies are used on this website for the following third party services: Google Analytics, LinkedIn Follow button, Facebook Like Button, Twitter Follow button, Google +1 button, AddThis social bookmarking tool, and our free daily newsletter ‘Sign Up!’ lightbox. Some of these services may be used to track your behaviour on other websites and we have no control over this.

By continuing to use this website without adjusting your browser’s cookie settings, you agree that we can place these cookies on your device.

If you choose to neither accept or decline the use of cookies on our website, but then click on a link to another page on our website, then dot rising will assume that you have accepted consent to using cookies.

**Other Sites**  
This privacy statement applies only to information collected by www.dotrising.com.  
Please be aware that .rising takes no responsibility for the privacy practices of other websites that are not owned or controlled by .rising but may be linked to from our website. If you are concerned with Privacy issues arising from these linked websites, we encourage you to be aware when you leaving our web domain and to read the privacy statements of each website that you visit.

In some select instances, we may pass the contact details that you have provided us with to a third party directly related to the service you have submitted those details for.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**  
If we decide, in the future, to change our policy on either gathering or analysing data, we undertake to reflect this in the privacy statement of this website.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.

**Statement created** : July 18th 2013

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [info@dotrising.com](mailto:info@dotrising.com)
